<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xml:base="http://ingedental.com"  xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<channel>
 <title>Andrew Inge - memorial day</title>
 <link>http://ingedental.com/tags/memorial-day</link>
 <description></description>
 <language>en</language>
<item>
 <title>Happy Memorial Day with a Story</title>
 <link>http://ingedental.com/blog/happy-memorial-day-story</link>
 <description>&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-body field-type-text-with-summary field-label-hidden&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-item even&quot; property=&quot;content:encoded&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Lt Col Inge&quot; class=&quot;float-left&quot; src=&quot;/sites/default/files/styles/blog_half_width/public/blog/inge_lg2.jpg?itok=f3c25wp0&quot; title=&quot;Lt Col Inge&quot; width=&quot;290&quot; height=&quot;223&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of us know that Memorial Day is about more than a day off with hot dogs and hamburgers. It&#039;s about honoring the men and women who have served our country in the military, many to the point of giving their lives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today I have a story for you. It&#039;s about my Dad (although he was &quot;Pop&quot; to all of us, never &quot;Dad or Daddy&quot;). As a twenty-eight year old Lt. Col. in the Corps of Engineers, he was sent to Europe just after the Battle of the Bulge. While searching for a location to build a bridge, he was strafed by a Nazi warplane and severely wounded. When the ambulance picked him up he was almost dead from loss of blood. The ambulance driver, unfamiliar with the terrain, drifted across enemy lines. My Dad was familiar with the maps of the area, and as wounded as he was, he was able to steer them back to friendly territory. Eventually they got him to a hospital, and he survived (or I would not be here telling you this story).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now fast forward to 2005, shortly after Hurricane Katrina hit Louisiana. I got a phone call at my dental office from a General Inge. As a rule I don&#039;t take phone calls while I&#039;m working with a patient, but this time I made an exception. As it turned out, General Inge was responsible for the Army Corps of Engineer&#039;s role in the clean up after the hurricane. He had gotten a phone call from an elderly gentleman who had heard his name on television and was calling the general to see if he was my Dad&#039;s son (me). The general got me in touch with the man, and it turned out he was the first person to get to my dad after he was shot. He did as much as he could to staunch the blood until the medic&#039;s arrived, effectively saving my dad&#039;s life. While recuperating from his wounds, my dad met my mother, and here I am.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a side story, the man who saved my dad&#039;s life was later wounded, and someone else was fundamental in saving HIS life. Stories like this about our veterans abound. We owe them a debt we cannot repay.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-field-tags field-type-taxonomy-term-reference field-label-above&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-label&quot;&gt;Tags:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-item even&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/tags/memorial-day&quot; typeof=&quot;skos:Concept&quot; property=&quot;rdfs:label skos:prefLabel&quot; datatype=&quot;&quot;&gt;memorial day&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-item odd&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/tags/veterans&quot; typeof=&quot;skos:Concept&quot; property=&quot;rdfs:label skos:prefLabel&quot; datatype=&quot;&quot;&gt;veterans&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
 <pubDate>Tue, 26 May 2015 12:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Dr. Inge</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">141 at http://ingedental.com</guid>
 <comments>http://ingedental.com/blog/happy-memorial-day-story#comments</comments>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
