<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xml:base="http://ingedental.com"  xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<channel>
 <title>Andrew Inge - root canals</title>
 <link>http://ingedental.com/tags/root-canals</link>
 <description></description>
 <language>en</language>
<item>
 <title>Dead Nerves can be Killers</title>
 <link>http://ingedental.com/blog/dead-nerves-can-be-killers</link>
 <description>&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-body field-type-text-with-summary field-label-hidden&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-item even&quot; property=&quot;content:encoded&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Painful toothache&quot; class=&quot;float-left&quot; src=&quot;/sites/default/files/styles/blog_full_width/public/blog/shutterstock_239115418.jpg?itok=cD0qnByq&quot; title=&quot;Pressure = Pain&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;334&quot; /&gt;Occasionally the nerve of a tooth dies. This is usually caused by a deep cavity that touches the nerve, or an injury that exposes the nerve to air or saliva. Once a nerve begins to die, it is usually irreversible. It won’t bounce back. If left alone, the dead tissue forms an infection and develops puss. This is what is called an abscess. This puss formation builds up pressure within the canal. The pressure works its way out to the tip of the root.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now this is where it gets interesting. During this process there is one thing you might want to keep in mind. &lt;strong&gt;PRESSURE=PAIN&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bone can’t stand infection. In fact, it kind of dissolves in the face of it. So, if the infection builds up slowly, the bone has a chance to dissolve at about the same rate. Very little pressure builds up. This means there is very little pain. If the infection builds up quickly, pressure builds up, and, you got it-- this leads to serious pain. But the process is sneaky. The bone can slowly dissolve without a person even being aware of it. A person can have a huge abscess and not even know it is there. But here’s the kicker. At any point in time, the abscess can start building up at a faster pace. The dissolving bone can’t keep up with it, pressure builds up, and wham! You know what happens then.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is where things can take a fascinating turn. When pressure is high and pain is through the roof, occasionally the pressure will break through the bone and escape into the surrounding soft tissue. That is when the swollen face commonly associated with abscesses develops. It can look awful. Then something curious happens. THE PAIN GOES AWAY! At least for a while.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The body does not like infection. It is serious stuff. An infection from an abscessed tooth can damage other organs in the body. It can actually kill people if untreated. In some undeveloped countries it is one of the leading causes of death. So if the abscess is detected at any of the stages mentioned above, a decision has to be made. The tooth can either be extracted or saved with a root canal and crown. But, obviously, something needs to be done.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-field-tags field-type-taxonomy-term-reference field-label-above&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-label&quot;&gt;Tags:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-item even&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/tags/root-canals&quot; typeof=&quot;skos:Concept&quot; property=&quot;rdfs:label skos:prefLabel&quot; datatype=&quot;&quot;&gt;root canals&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-item odd&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/tags/crowns&quot; typeof=&quot;skos:Concept&quot; property=&quot;rdfs:label skos:prefLabel&quot; datatype=&quot;&quot;&gt;crowns&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-item even&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/tags/abscess&quot; typeof=&quot;skos:Concept&quot; property=&quot;rdfs:label skos:prefLabel&quot; datatype=&quot;&quot;&gt;abscess&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
 <pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2015 15:30:57 +0000</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Dr. Inge</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">133 at http://ingedental.com</guid>
 <comments>http://ingedental.com/blog/dead-nerves-can-be-killers#comments</comments>
</item>
<item>
 <title>The Roots are Not the Root of the Problem</title>
 <link>http://ingedental.com/blog/roots-are-not-root-problem</link>
 <description>&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-body field-type-text-with-summary field-label-hidden&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-item even&quot; property=&quot;content:encoded&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Anatomy of a healthy tooth &amp;amp;amp; nerves&quot; class=&quot;float-left&quot; src=&quot;/sites/default/files/styles/blog_half_width/public/blog/Root%20Canal%201_0.jpg?itok=OTZY5nUa&quot; title=&quot;Diagram of healthy tooth and nerve&quot; width=&quot;290&quot; height=&quot;357&quot; /&gt;Few things strike fear in the hearts of dental patients like the words “root canal”.  And probably for good reason.  Years ago they could be extremely painful, especially if the tooth was abscessed.  Times have changed now.  There is really nothing to fear about root canals but perhaps boredom.  Though relatively painless, they are still usually long procedures.   Yet, the reputation persists.  There is a lot of misunderstanding about root canals that lead to a high anxiety level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A lot of people are under the misconception that root canals involve the removal of one of the roots of a tooth.  Now that DOES sound painful!  But actually that is not the case.  The roots are not removed. Boring for sure (and perhaps a little painful for you non-academic types), but a little anatomy lesson might be appropriate here.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The roots of teeth are what anchor the teeth into the bone.  Front teeth usually have one root. Back teeth usually have two, three or sometimes four.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Healthy teeth are not like fingernails or hair.  Cut a fingernail or hair, and nothing hurts.  Cut into a tooth and it &lt;em&gt;hurts&lt;/em&gt;. Teeth are very much a living part of your body. Teeth have nerves and a blood supply.  This bundle of nerves, veins, and arteries branch off from a larger bundle in the body, and go up the middle of the root.  The drawing at the top of this blog shows a lower molar with two roots and bundles going up the middle of each root.  The nerves come together in the middle of the tooth (called the pulp chamber), giving the nervous system a horseshoe appearance.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So to get back to the misconception we were talking about, it is this nerve in the canal that is removed in a root canal, not the root itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let us know in the comments below, have you had a root canal? How did it go?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-field-tags field-type-taxonomy-term-reference field-label-above&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-label&quot;&gt;Tags:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-item even&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/tags/root-canals&quot; typeof=&quot;skos:Concept&quot; property=&quot;rdfs:label skos:prefLabel&quot; datatype=&quot;&quot;&gt;root canals&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
 <pubDate>Wed, 13 May 2015 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Dr. Inge</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">132 at http://ingedental.com</guid>
 <comments>http://ingedental.com/blog/roots-are-not-root-problem#comments</comments>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
