<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xml:base="http://ingedental.com"  xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<channel>
 <title>Andrew Inge - sleep apnea</title>
 <link>http://ingedental.com/tags/sleep-apnea</link>
 <description></description>
 <language>en</language>
<item>
 <title>Sleep is not just for the sleepy </title>
 <link>http://ingedental.com/blog/sleep-not-just-sleepy</link>
 <description>&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-body field-type-text-with-summary field-label-hidden&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-item even&quot; property=&quot;content:encoded&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/sites/default/files/blog/9/Sleep%20Apnea-1_0.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Sleep Apnea&quot; title=&quot;Sleep Apnea&quot; width=&quot;150&quot; height=&quot;225&quot; class=&quot;float-right&quot; /&gt;Who needs sleep? We all do, of course.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However most people who have spent much time in school are aware of all-nighters. Most of us have envied that occasional student who only needed four hours of sleep a night, yet could ace the test the next morning and party all afternoon. Somehow being able to get away with less sleep seems something to be desired. Think of it. If we could cut out just one hour of sleep a night, and there are 365 nights a year, we are adding 365 hours that we are awake per year!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But for most of us mere mortals, that&#039;s a dangerous way of thinking. Most of us can push through one or two nights with minimum sleep, but even then our performance level suffers dramatically. We have memory loss, we can&#039;t focus, and we suffer depression, moodiness, and short tempers. Yet, after a few nights of normal sleep we can bounce back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, the effects of sleep deprivation are accumulative. Normal sleep for most people means 7-8 hours of sound sleep. Within that range each individual has their optimal time. Any deviation from this optimal time consistently can have severe consequences. The problems mentioned above are magnified, and other more serious physiological changes can occur. Even the potential for a heart attack or stroke can dramatically increase. The brain needs that optimal amount of sleep to regenerate itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some people feel good about cutting out several hours of sleep during the week, and then try to catch up on the weekends. If you care about optimal performance and health, this doesn&#039;t work. By Thursday or Friday the effects have added up, and your health, relationships, and ability to focus and be productive at work suffers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remember the three-legged stool of health we keep mentioning—diet, rest, and exercise. Cut any of these short, and something has to give!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A huge portion of our population suffers from sleep disorders. And dentistry can help. Please call our office if you experience any of the symptoms mentioned in our previous post. Many have found relief from what dentistry can provide. And for those of you who have already been diagnosed with sleep apnea and wear a CPAP—something that most people detest--dentistry can let you put that thing in the drawer for good! (Check out the photo—yikes!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, it is true that modern dentistry can be life changing in the area of cosmetic dentistry, tooth colored fillings, bonding, etc., but there are few things that can have more impact than the benefits of consistently getting a good night sleep.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-field-tags field-type-taxonomy-term-reference field-label-above&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-label&quot;&gt;Tags:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-item even&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/tags/sleep-apnea&quot; typeof=&quot;skos:Concept&quot; property=&quot;rdfs:label skos:prefLabel&quot; datatype=&quot;&quot;&gt;sleep apnea&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
 <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2013 20:46:12 +0000</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Dr. Inge</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">126 at http://ingedental.com</guid>
 <comments>http://ingedental.com/blog/sleep-not-just-sleepy#comments</comments>
</item>
<item>
 <title>Snoring and Sleep Apnea - The not so silent killers</title>
 <link>http://ingedental.com/blog/snoring-and-sleep-apnea-not-so-silent-killers</link>
 <description>&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-body field-type-text-with-summary field-label-hidden&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-item even&quot; property=&quot;content:encoded&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Is snoring bothering you?&quot; class=&quot;float-left&quot; height=&quot;109&quot; src=&quot;/sites/default/files/blog/8/Snoring_1.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Is snoring bothering you?&quot; width=&quot;150&quot; /&gt;Recently we were working with a man with severe snoring problems. His snoring was so loud he and his wife had resorted to sleeping in separate bedrooms. As he realized his treatment was likely to be successful, he agreed to follow through with it under one condition. We were not to tell his wife he had stopped snoring.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He said he had gotten to like sleeping in separate bed rooms. He could make as much of a mess as he liked without being nagged to straighten things up. Another big benefit was that there were no more fights over the TV remote. Living in separate bedrooms was actually helping their marriage!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Things to know about snoring:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Snoring is often related to sleep apnea. Snoring is caused by a flap of tissue at the back of the throat fluttering up and down, narrowing the airway. When the airway gets too narrow, it can block the flow of air almost completely. The sleeping person can actually stop breathing for a few seconds or longer. It can happen many times throughout the night. This causes a sleep disturbance, often to the point of causing the person to wake up. The technical name for this is obstructive sleep apnea, or OSA. It is associated with a multitude of problems, including even death.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dentistry has long been associated just with fillings, dentures, crown and bridge, cleanings, etc. Now it is a vital partner with physicians and technicians in the area of sleep medicine, or specifically, sleep dentistry.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Symptoms of Obstructive Sleep Apnea:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Loud snoring&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Excessive daytime sleepiness&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Depression&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fatigue&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reduced resistance to infection&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Choking or Gasping for breath&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;In our next blog we will discuss this dangerous condition a bit further. With so many people out there who are affected by it, many without even knowing it, sleep apnea is an important topic. It is associated with many dangerous conditions. Knowledge and treatment of it can truly be a life saver.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-field-tags field-type-taxonomy-term-reference field-label-above&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-label&quot;&gt;Tags:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-item even&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/tags/snoring&quot; typeof=&quot;skos:Concept&quot; property=&quot;rdfs:label skos:prefLabel&quot; datatype=&quot;&quot;&gt;snoring&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-item odd&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/tags/sleep-apnea&quot; typeof=&quot;skos:Concept&quot; property=&quot;rdfs:label skos:prefLabel&quot; datatype=&quot;&quot;&gt;sleep apnea&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-item even&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/tags/osa&quot; typeof=&quot;skos:Concept&quot; property=&quot;rdfs:label skos:prefLabel&quot; datatype=&quot;&quot;&gt;OSA&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-item odd&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/tags/obstructive-sleep-apnea&quot; typeof=&quot;skos:Concept&quot; property=&quot;rdfs:label skos:prefLabel&quot; datatype=&quot;&quot;&gt;obstructive sleep apnea&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
 <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2013 20:18:36 +0000</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Dr. Inge</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">125 at http://ingedental.com</guid>
 <comments>http://ingedental.com/blog/snoring-and-sleep-apnea-not-so-silent-killers#comments</comments>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
