<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xml:base="http://ingedental.com"  xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<channel>
 <title>Andrew Inge - procrastination</title>
 <link>http://ingedental.com/tags/procrastination</link>
 <description></description>
 <language>en</language>
<item>
 <title>Satan and Good Health</title>
 <link>http://ingedental.com/blog/satan-and-good-health</link>
 <description>&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-body field-type-text-with-summary field-label-hidden&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-item even&quot; property=&quot;content:encoded&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/sites/default/files/blog/iStock_000002060878XSmall_0.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Devil mask&quot; title=&quot;Devil mask&quot; width=&quot;120&quot; height=&quot;179&quot; class=&quot;float-right&quot; /&gt; In his book, Tide Rising, Bruce Theileman tells an interesting story. Here is a VERY modified version:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;One day Satan gathered his demons and asked for a volunteer to come up with a message to deliver that would ruin men&#039;s souls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first volunteer said, &quot;I will tell them there is no heaven.&quot; Satan replied, &quot;They will not believe you, for there is a bit of heaven in every human heart. You may not go.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second volunteer said, &quot;I will tell them there is no hell.&quot; Satan replied, &quot;They will not believe you, for there is an inner voice in every human heart that says evil will be punished.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then from the darkest pit of hell came a volunteer who said, &quot;Send me and I will tell them &#039;there is no hurry&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Satan said, &quot;Go&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A bit theological, perhaps, but this story pertains a lot to human health. Procrastination, especially in matters of health, lies deep within the human heart. &quot;I&#039;ll start watching what I eat tomorrow.&quot; &quot;I will start exercising tomorrow.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Good dental care is no exception. People continue to lose teeth do to—procrastination. Procrastination in brushing and flossing. Procrastination in that all important six month checkup. Procrastination in getting that tooth colored filling or crown done that was diagnosed months ago. The longer things go untreated, the worse things are when treatment is absolutely necessary and procrastination is impossible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That being said, however, dentistry is on the cutting edge of making procrastination difficult. A terrific smile and fresh breath is the model in a huge number of commercials. And the best way to get that, obviously, is routine brushing and flossing and routine dental checkups every six months. Cosmetic dentistry and bleaching can give you that TV commercial smile. In this technological age, we make things easy. We offer many ways to make appointments online. We can send out multiple reminders of appointments by email or text.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So don&#039;t believe it the next time the demon says there is no hurry. The best time to take care of your teeth is now.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-field-tags field-type-taxonomy-term-reference field-label-above&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-label&quot;&gt;Tags:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-item even&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/tags/procrastination&quot; typeof=&quot;skos:Concept&quot; property=&quot;rdfs:label skos:prefLabel&quot; datatype=&quot;&quot;&gt;procrastination&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-item odd&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/tags/dental-health&quot; typeof=&quot;skos:Concept&quot; property=&quot;rdfs:label skos:prefLabel&quot; datatype=&quot;&quot;&gt;dental health&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-item even&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/tags/brushing&quot; typeof=&quot;skos:Concept&quot; property=&quot;rdfs:label skos:prefLabel&quot; datatype=&quot;&quot;&gt;brushing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-item odd&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/tags/flossing&quot; typeof=&quot;skos:Concept&quot; property=&quot;rdfs:label skos:prefLabel&quot; datatype=&quot;&quot;&gt;flossing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-item even&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/tags/checkup&quot; typeof=&quot;skos:Concept&quot; property=&quot;rdfs:label skos:prefLabel&quot; datatype=&quot;&quot;&gt;checkup&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
 <pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2013 01:24:20 +0000</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Dr. Inge</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">128 at http://ingedental.com</guid>
 <comments>http://ingedental.com/blog/satan-and-good-health#comments</comments>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
