<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xml:base="http://ingedental.com"  xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<channel>
 <title>Andrew Inge - bonding</title>
 <link>http://ingedental.com/tags/bonding</link>
 <description></description>
 <language>en</language>
<item>
 <title>Bonding 101</title>
 <link>http://ingedental.com/blog/bonding-101</link>
 <description>&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-body field-type-text-with-summary field-label-hidden&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-item even&quot; property=&quot;content:encoded&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/sites/default/files/blog/medium_snowflakes.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Snowflakes&quot; title=&quot;Snowflakes&quot; width=&quot;120&quot; height=&quot;120&quot; class=&quot;float-left&quot; /&gt;As I sit here, it is a beautiful Saturday morning with six inches of pristine snow blanketing the ground and a clear blue sky. We often hear of the calm before the storm, but this is the calm after the storm. It is quiet. It is nice. The night&#039;s blizzard left a lot of the Northeast clobbered with a huge amount of snow. This resulted in all kinds of power outages and stalled, if not stopped, transportation systems. Unlike with hurricane Sandy and its power outages, we in the Lehigh Valley got off very easy. With the storm starting Friday evening, most of us didn&#039;t even miss much work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today&#039;s topic is dental bonding. Almost everyone has heard of bonding. It can be explained very simply, or it can get quite complex. Almost every dental journal has at least something about the science, the techniques, the materials, or the color schemes used in bonding. Since we get so many questions about it, I thought I&#039;d give a very basic explanation of bonding—what it is, and how it works.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bonding started out as a way of filling cavities in the front teeth with something tooth colored. For most of the twentieth century front teeth were filled with gold or a white silicate. Occasionally you would actually see an amalgam in a front tooth. All of these solutions were very unsightly, and except for the gold, didn&#039;t last very long and had to be replaced. Then composite fillings were invented. This was tooth colored, which was a great improvement. All of these, though, were kept in the tooth mechanically, that is, with undercuts cut into the tooth that held them in place. In all of these there was no &quot;glue&quot; that kept them in the tooth. Therefore there was always a microscopic gap between the filling material and the tooth. This gap would eventually fill up with bacteria, stain, or decay, and even the tooth colored composites would look bad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then came bonding. The basic idea of bonding is very simple. With a very mild acid, small holes are etched into the enamel or dentin of the tooth. Then a liquid resin is made to flow into those holes and get hard when a light is applied to it. On top of the resin layer, the composite filling material is placed. The composite filling material is made up of tiny glass beads immersed in a liquid resin. This results in a putty like material than can be sculpted to the desired shape and hardened by being exposed to the light. It forms a chemical bond to the resin liquid that is already bonded to the holes that were etched into the tooth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are several huge advantages of bonded fillings compared to the previous types of fillings. For one thing, there are no gaps between the filling and the tooth that might allow bacteria and stain to move in. (There is a thing called micro leakage that occurs over time, but hey, we&#039;re not going to get too technical here.) Another great advantage is that since the filling is bonded to the tooth (think glued), undercuts are not necessary to hold it in. This means less of the tooth is cut away to make undercuts, and this means that the tooth is stronger. In fact, some fillings can be bonded directly on the surface of a tooth without any cutting the tooth at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Originally, composites were not strong enough to be used in back teeth. The mouth can be thought of as a nut cracker, with the greatest forces towards the back, or the hinge. So the farther you go back in the mouth, the stronger the forces when chewing. This is why molars are so much larger and stronger than front teeth. Therefore, filling materials that do quite well in front teeth, where the forces are weaker, just might not be strong enough to hold up in the back teeth. And that was the case with the earlier composites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In later blogs we will be going over how advance bonding can help you, the dental patient.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Question:&lt;/strong&gt; Is there anyone out there who has had an experience with bonding in their own mouths? How did things go?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-field-tags field-type-taxonomy-term-reference field-label-above&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-label&quot;&gt;Tags:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-item even&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/tags/bonding&quot; typeof=&quot;skos:Concept&quot; property=&quot;rdfs:label skos:prefLabel&quot; datatype=&quot;&quot;&gt;bonding&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
 <pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2013 16:57:55 +0000</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Dr. Inge</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">123 at http://ingedental.com</guid>
 <comments>http://ingedental.com/blog/bonding-101#comments</comments>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
