<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xml:base="http://ingedental.com"  xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<channel>
 <title>Andrew Inge - abscess</title>
 <link>http://ingedental.com/tags/abscess</link>
 <description></description>
 <language>en</language>
<item>
 <title>Dead Nerves can be Killers</title>
 <link>http://ingedental.com/blog/dead-nerves-can-be-killers</link>
 <description>&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-body field-type-text-with-summary field-label-hidden&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-item even&quot; property=&quot;content:encoded&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Painful toothache&quot; class=&quot;float-left&quot; src=&quot;/sites/default/files/styles/blog_full_width/public/blog/shutterstock_239115418.jpg?itok=cD0qnByq&quot; title=&quot;Pressure = Pain&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;334&quot; /&gt;Occasionally the nerve of a tooth dies. This is usually caused by a deep cavity that touches the nerve, or an injury that exposes the nerve to air or saliva. Once a nerve begins to die, it is usually irreversible. It won’t bounce back. If left alone, the dead tissue forms an infection and develops puss. This is what is called an abscess. This puss formation builds up pressure within the canal. The pressure works its way out to the tip of the root.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now this is where it gets interesting. During this process there is one thing you might want to keep in mind. &lt;strong&gt;PRESSURE=PAIN&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bone can’t stand infection. In fact, it kind of dissolves in the face of it. So, if the infection builds up slowly, the bone has a chance to dissolve at about the same rate. Very little pressure builds up. This means there is very little pain. If the infection builds up quickly, pressure builds up, and, you got it-- this leads to serious pain. But the process is sneaky. The bone can slowly dissolve without a person even being aware of it. A person can have a huge abscess and not even know it is there. But here’s the kicker. At any point in time, the abscess can start building up at a faster pace. The dissolving bone can’t keep up with it, pressure builds up, and wham! You know what happens then.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is where things can take a fascinating turn. When pressure is high and pain is through the roof, occasionally the pressure will break through the bone and escape into the surrounding soft tissue. That is when the swollen face commonly associated with abscesses develops. It can look awful. Then something curious happens. THE PAIN GOES AWAY! At least for a while.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The body does not like infection. It is serious stuff. An infection from an abscessed tooth can damage other organs in the body. It can actually kill people if untreated. In some undeveloped countries it is one of the leading causes of death. So if the abscess is detected at any of the stages mentioned above, a decision has to be made. The tooth can either be extracted or saved with a root canal and crown. But, obviously, something needs to be done.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-field-tags field-type-taxonomy-term-reference field-label-above&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-label&quot;&gt;Tags:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-item even&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/tags/root-canals&quot; typeof=&quot;skos:Concept&quot; property=&quot;rdfs:label skos:prefLabel&quot; datatype=&quot;&quot;&gt;root canals&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-item odd&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/tags/crowns&quot; typeof=&quot;skos:Concept&quot; property=&quot;rdfs:label skos:prefLabel&quot; datatype=&quot;&quot;&gt;crowns&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-item even&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/tags/abscess&quot; typeof=&quot;skos:Concept&quot; property=&quot;rdfs:label skos:prefLabel&quot; datatype=&quot;&quot;&gt;abscess&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
 <pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2015 15:30:57 +0000</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Dr. Inge</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">133 at http://ingedental.com</guid>
 <comments>http://ingedental.com/blog/dead-nerves-can-be-killers#comments</comments>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
