<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xml:base="http://ingedental.com"  xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<channel>
 <title>Andrew Inge - dentures</title>
 <link>http://ingedental.com/tags/dentures</link>
 <description></description>
 <language>en</language>
<item>
 <title>It&#039;s Never Too Late</title>
 <link>http://ingedental.com/blog/its-never-too-late</link>
 <description>&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-body field-type-text-with-summary field-label-hidden&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-item even&quot; property=&quot;content:encoded&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/sites/default/files/blog/medium_iPhone.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;iphone&quot; title=&quot;iPhone&quot; width=&quot;120&quot; height=&quot;120&quot; class=&quot;float-right&quot; /&gt;Those of you who have an iPhone know they come with a little app in the form of a yellow note pad. I use it a lot. Starting years ago, I would enter the name of a book I wanted to read, or a movie I wanted to see, and I had a running list going. Or the idea of a Christmas or birthday present would come to mind and noted. There would be a website mentioned somewhere I wanted to visit, or a quote I wanted to remember. Kept some passwords to some non-sensitive sites, too. Over time, a lot of information accumulated on this seemingly insignificant little note pad that I just took for granted. And then last week, I flipped open the pad and got the single message, &quot;no notes found&quot;. In a second, it was all gone. Not a trace of all that information was there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As those who have iPhones and iPads know, unlike with PCs, there is no &quot;save&quot; button on them. They just seem to have naked apps hanging in the wind. All that information I had taken for granted for years seemed to be gone. And I mean GONE gone. I couldn&#039;t believe how much I missed it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But, there was something out there I didn&#039;t know about or understand. It is called the &quot;iCloud&quot;. Billions or maybe trillions of pieces of information are out there floating around through the air. Somewhere in that mess was all the information that I had on my note pad. All I had to do was sinc my phone to the iCloud with the help of iTunes, and PRESTO, my little yellow pad was back. Take home lesson? With modern technology, there is always hope. Maybe things that seem gone are not really gone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The same is true in dentistry. There is always hope. Maybe things that seem gone are not really gone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is no question that like in so many other areas of life, prevention is the name of the game. Most good dental offices stress prevention very strongly. Cleanings, x-rays, thorough examinations—all play a big part in oral health.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, when prevention is not followed over the years and oral health is neglected, disaster can strike. People can lose teeth, suffer tremendous pain, or expose their bodies to toxic materials that can seriously affect their overall health. The good news is that with modern dentistry there is always hope. It is never too late to restore function and appearance. Even if every tooth is lost, it is never too late.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many new patients come into the office for the first time extremely embarrassed over the state of their mouth. A big part of our task as health professionals is to reassure them that one of the reasons for our existence as dentists is to help out people who are in bad shape when it comes to their oral health. There is no cause for shame here. When we can offer them hope without any judgmentalism, you can almost see the lights come on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A big part of why some people neglect their teeth for years is fear and uncertainty. Words like crowns, root canals, dentures, etc., strike fear into their hearts. For these people, we back up a little, establish a trusting relationship, and do a little friendly educating. Fear and apprehension change into hope and anticipation. This is what we build on to restore people to good oral health. For most of our patients we can show that there really are alternatives, that there is hope, that we have something to build on. It&#039;s not too late.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a point where teeth are unsalvageable. Or maybe they are actually GONE already. Or have been gone for many, many years. The &quot;save&quot; button has been gone too long and there is no Cloud. Even here, modern dentistry can come to the rescue with options it never has had before. We can offer new techniques and new technologies in denture and partial denture fabrication, and we can use implants in a variety of ways that can restore function and beauty. There is always hope. That is why it is so much fun being a dentist.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-field-tags field-type-taxonomy-term-reference field-label-above&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-label&quot;&gt;Tags:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-item even&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/tags/prevention&quot; typeof=&quot;skos:Concept&quot; property=&quot;rdfs:label skos:prefLabel&quot; datatype=&quot;&quot;&gt;prevention&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-item odd&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/tags/hope&quot; typeof=&quot;skos:Concept&quot; property=&quot;rdfs:label skos:prefLabel&quot; datatype=&quot;&quot;&gt;hope&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-item even&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/tags/oral-health&quot; typeof=&quot;skos:Concept&quot; property=&quot;rdfs:label skos:prefLabel&quot; datatype=&quot;&quot;&gt;oral health&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-item odd&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/tags/dentures&quot; typeof=&quot;skos:Concept&quot; property=&quot;rdfs:label skos:prefLabel&quot; datatype=&quot;&quot;&gt;dentures&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-item even&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/tags/denture-fabrication&quot; typeof=&quot;skos:Concept&quot; property=&quot;rdfs:label skos:prefLabel&quot; datatype=&quot;&quot;&gt;denture fabrication&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-item odd&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/tags/implants&quot; typeof=&quot;skos:Concept&quot; property=&quot;rdfs:label skos:prefLabel&quot; datatype=&quot;&quot;&gt;implants&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
 <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2013 21:58:58 +0000</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Dr. Inge</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">124 at http://ingedental.com</guid>
 <comments>http://ingedental.com/blog/its-never-too-late#comments</comments>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
