<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xml:base="http://ingedental.com"  xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<channel>
 <title>Andrew Inge - children</title>
 <link>http://ingedental.com/tags/children</link>
 <description></description>
 <language>en</language>
<item>
 <title>Dentistry For Our Kids</title>
 <link>http://ingedental.com/blog/dentistry-our-kids</link>
 <description>&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-body field-type-text-with-summary field-label-hidden&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-item even&quot; property=&quot;content:encoded&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/sites/default/files/blog/medium_ChildatDentist.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Child at Dentist&quot; title=&quot;Child at Dentist&quot; width=&quot;120&quot; height=&quot;120&quot; class=&quot;float-right&quot; /&gt;Anyone who follows us on Facebook can tell you we at IngeDental really get a kick out of treating kids. Here are a few tips that can make their visits a lot more fun:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Start Young&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The best time for a dentist to see your child is somewhere between 1 and 2 years of age. Usually this will be about the time most of the baby teeth are in.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Have a &quot;Happy Visit&quot;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This should be made sometime before the child&#039;s first appointment. It usually is in conjunction with a parent&#039;s cleaning appointment. The child just gets to watch and play with the toys. This first visit should not be at a time when the parent is getting any other dental work done. The sights (think Sharp Things) and sounds (think Drill) can be disturbing, not reassuring.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Keep It Simple&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When preparing for a visit, don&#039;t provide too many details. Since kids don&#039;t really understand the details, they only create room for unwelcome imaginations. Tell them the hygienist will look in their mouths and count their teeth. That&#039;s all they need to know! And at an early age, that is usually about all that is going to happen. Children don&#039;t usually know (or care) they are getting an examination!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Never use a dental visit as a punishment or threat.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Never bribe your child.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Watch the fathers!&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Children seem to mainly pay attention to the emotional reactions of the fathers when deciding if situations at the dentist are potentially stressful. But remember, children are experts at picking up anxiety from either the father or the mother. If you don&#039;t feel comfortable about being in a dental office, most experts agree, this is one time when it is ok to just…Fake It!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Watch the language.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Certain words should never be mentioned when trying to reassure your child about going to the dentist. Pain, Hurt, Sharp, Pinch, Needle, and Drill— just to name a few. If you want to see your child&#039;s eyes get wide, just say something like, &quot;Honest honey, that sharp needle doesn&#039;t hurt TOO much. It&#039;s just a pinch. And although the drill is loud, it doesn&#039;t cause much pain at all.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;We hope these suggestions will help your child&#039;s dental visit be a happy one. Modern dentistry is more comfortable than ever, and starting your child off with good experiences at the dental office will reap benefits for life.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-field-tags field-type-taxonomy-term-reference field-label-above&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-label&quot;&gt;Tags:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-item even&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/tags/dentistry&quot; typeof=&quot;skos:Concept&quot; property=&quot;rdfs:label skos:prefLabel&quot; datatype=&quot;&quot;&gt;dentistry&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-item odd&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/tags/children&quot; typeof=&quot;skos:Concept&quot; property=&quot;rdfs:label skos:prefLabel&quot; datatype=&quot;&quot;&gt;children&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
 <pubDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2013 13:41:57 +0000</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Dr. Inge</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">122 at http://ingedental.com</guid>
 <comments>http://ingedental.com/blog/dentistry-our-kids#comments</comments>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
