<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xml:base="http://ingedental.com"  xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<channel>
 <title>Andrew Inge - health</title>
 <link>http://ingedental.com/tags/health</link>
 <description></description>
 <language>en</language>
<item>
 <title>Sitting Can Be Dangerous (part 2)</title>
 <link>http://ingedental.com/blog/sitting-can-be-dangerous-part-2</link>
 <description>&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-body field-type-text-with-summary field-label-hidden&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-item even&quot; property=&quot;content:encoded&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;float-left&quot; src=&quot;/sites/default/files/styles/blog_full_width/public/blog/Fitbit%20Walk.jpg?itok=JkWYczXw&quot; width=&quot;580&quot; height=&quot;435&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you should by chance see some of our staff walking around in our parking lot, it does not mean we have been sniffing too much laughing gas. Honest. Here Amy and Pam take advantage of some of the latest technology on the planet. It appears the world now acknowledges what we wrote two blogs ago—sitting can be dangerous.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A whole industry has sprung up around this idea. It is about the advent of what are called &quot;Activity Watches&quot;. As we all know, watches are not just watches anymore. They can tell you just about anything. But Activity Watches have taken this idea to an entirely new level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They can actually tell you that you have been sitting too long, and you need to get up and walk around in the parking lot. (Amy and Pam are our front desk people, and that requires a lot of sitting.) They can also tell you your sleep patterns that come with alarms when you have stopped breathing, the calories you have burned, when you have gone up or down steps, and your heart rate. Not to mention that they also come with a GPS tracker, caller ID, music control and notifications, an app for your phone that you can use for seeing your activity history and for setting activity goals, and a few other things that come with different manufacturers and models.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As an aside, they can also tell you the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google &quot;Activity Watches&quot; and you will see how popular they have become. There are about a zillion makes and models. Not to mention the zillions of colors available. Some even have interchangeable bands of different colors. You can be color coordinated with any outfit. And the price? Once again, you have a zillion options, depending on what features you want.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of us here at the office use the watches made by Fitbit. We like their size and affordability. Check out their website at &lt;a href=&quot;http://Fitbit.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Fitbit.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is this a fad? Who knows. But they can definitely make you healthier and get you in better shape. Who would have thought a watch could extend your lifetime?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-field-tags field-type-taxonomy-term-reference field-label-above&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-label&quot;&gt;Tags:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-item even&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/tags/health&quot; typeof=&quot;skos:Concept&quot; property=&quot;rdfs:label skos:prefLabel&quot; datatype=&quot;&quot;&gt;health&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
 <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Dr. Inge</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">153 at http://ingedental.com</guid>
 <comments>http://ingedental.com/blog/sitting-can-be-dangerous-part-2#comments</comments>
</item>
<item>
 <title>Don’t Just Sit There!</title>
 <link>http://ingedental.com/blog/don%E2%80%99t-just-sit-there</link>
 <description>&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-body field-type-text-with-summary field-label-hidden&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-item even&quot; property=&quot;content:encoded&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;image-blog_full_width&quot; src=&quot;/sites/default/files/styles/blog_full_width/public/blog/don_t_just_sit_there.jpg?itok=fghOPpT1&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;216&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sitting can be dangerous! We posted on Facebook quite a while ago that there were some indications that sitting was dangerous. The post fell into the &quot;ho hum&quot; category, practically no one read it, and I&#039;m sure no one acted upon it, including myself. It kind of fell into the &quot;most things fun in life are either harmful or sinful&quot; category, and no one wants to hear about that kind of stuff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, unfortunately, it is official. Statistics are usually quick to put one into a drunken stupor. Especially unwanted statistics. So I will cover only a few. Yet they are important, because they involve a problem common to all of us. Death.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remember, good health is the fly wheel to the good life. But our sedentary American lifestyle wants to take us out. Don&#039;t take it sitting down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Sitting increases the risk of death. A person who sits for 6 or more hours a day is 40% more likely to die within 15 years than someone who sits for less than three hours a day. The average American sits for 9.3 hours a day. A huge number of them spend most of their workday sitting at a computer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sitting for prolonged periods of time increases the rate of obesity.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sitting jobs directly correlate to an increase of cardiovascular disease.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The negative effects of sitting a lot are immediate and not just something that occurs down the road.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There are mental and emotional effects of just sitting as well. We get more sluggish, our energy levels take a steep drop, and we become far less productive. All of this can contribute to a loss of self-esteem—a feeling of not being a worthwhile person.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-field-tags field-type-taxonomy-term-reference field-label-above&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-label&quot;&gt;Tags:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-item even&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/tags/health&quot; typeof=&quot;skos:Concept&quot; property=&quot;rdfs:label skos:prefLabel&quot; datatype=&quot;&quot;&gt;health&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
 <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2015 15:30:31 +0000</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Dr. Inge</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">151 at http://ingedental.com</guid>
 <comments>http://ingedental.com/blog/don%E2%80%99t-just-sit-there#comments</comments>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
