<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xml:base="http://ingedental.com"  xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<channel>
 <title>Andrew Inge - changes in dentistry</title>
 <link>http://ingedental.com/tags/changes-dentistry</link>
 <description></description>
 <language>en</language>
<item>
 <title>A Great Dental Experience, not Just a Dental Appointment.</title>
 <link>http://ingedental.com/blog/great-dental-experience-not-just-dental-appointment</link>
 <description>&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-body field-type-text-with-summary field-label-hidden&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-item even&quot; property=&quot;content:encoded&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;It is a great time for dental patients. Modern dentistry can help so many people in so many ways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I mentioned in our last post, dentistry is not the same as it was just a few years ago. And who benefits the most from this? You do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One constant in life is that the pace of change in almost every sphere is getting faster and faster. This is true in dentistry for sure. Remember how George Washington had to pull every single one of his teeth without any anesthetic? Well, things really didn&#039;t change much for over one hundred years. Sometime I should go over the high points of the history of dentistry, because it is interesting, but for now let&#039;s just say &quot;It ain&#039;t like the old days!&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/sites/default/files/blog/Stacey_0.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Stacey&quot; title=&quot;Stacey&quot; width=&quot;120&quot; height=&quot;160&quot; class=&quot;float-right&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The advances in today&#039;s dentistry are not just about the technology, although the technology is a big part of it. The focus is on the entire dental experience. In the last post I wrote about how even your phone call is handled differently. But that is just the starting point. If you are a new patient, most modern dental offices will let you send in your new patient registration and medical history information beforehand either online or by mail. This saves you a lot of time and hassles on your first visit. When you walk into the office you are welcomed with a warm greeting. The old sliding glass door and &quot;name, please&quot; welcome is a thing of the past.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &quot;waiting room&quot; is not actually a &quot;waiting&quot; room, although the name has kind of stuck. (Most dentists these days make a huge effort to be right on schedule with minimal waiting.) The room, whatever you want to call it, is well lit and patient friendly. You will right away notice the cleanliness and up to date reading materials. There is usually a corner with children&#039;s toys.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The whole atmosphere has the feeling of a warm welcome, not a cold medical facility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The whole focus is on you and making your visit a great experience, not just a dental appointment.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-field-tags field-type-taxonomy-term-reference field-label-above&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-label&quot;&gt;Tags:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-item even&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/tags/welcome&quot; typeof=&quot;skos:Concept&quot; property=&quot;rdfs:label skos:prefLabel&quot; datatype=&quot;&quot;&gt;welcome&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-item odd&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/tags/first-visit&quot; typeof=&quot;skos:Concept&quot; property=&quot;rdfs:label skos:prefLabel&quot; datatype=&quot;&quot;&gt;fIrst visit&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-item even&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/tags/changes-dentistry&quot; typeof=&quot;skos:Concept&quot; property=&quot;rdfs:label skos:prefLabel&quot; datatype=&quot;&quot;&gt;changes in dentistry&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
 <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jan 2013 03:13:51 +0000</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Dr. Inge</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">118 at http://ingedental.com</guid>
 <comments>http://ingedental.com/blog/great-dental-experience-not-just-dental-appointment#comments</comments>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
