<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xml:base="http://ingedental.com"  xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<channel>
 <title>Andrew Inge - teeth whitening</title>
 <link>http://ingedental.com/tags/teeth-whitening</link>
 <description></description>
 <language>en</language>
<item>
 <title>Brighten That Smile</title>
 <link>http://ingedental.com/blog/brighten-smile</link>
 <description>&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-body field-type-text-with-summary field-label-hidden&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-item even&quot; property=&quot;content:encoded&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Before and after whitening&quot; class=&quot;float-left&quot; src=&quot;/sites/default/files/styles/blog_half_width/public/blog/Bleach%202.jpg?itok=YoFBZ_ph&quot; title=&quot;Gentleman before and after whitening&quot; width=&quot;290&quot; height=&quot;195&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Years ago the whiteness of teeth wasn’t all that important for the general public, mostly because there was not much you could do about it.  Many people smoked and drank coffee and tea for years—all resulting in dingy looking teeth.  Tooth brushing was more for preventing cavities and improving the breath than improving the coloration of the teeth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Obviously, times have changed.  Arguably, people are more concerned now about the appearance of their teeth than at any time in our history.  Having straight white teeth these days is an integral part of our self-image.  It affects our social lives, our employment opportunities, and our overall sense of well-being.  And let’s face it.  Dingy yellow teeth look OLD—the curse of the times.  “Youthful” and “white teeth” just seem to go together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of the time getting a whiter smile is a quick fix.  Use one of the bleaching methods mentioned below and BAM!  White teeth. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, if your smile looks like a dingy yellow train wreck, it gets a little more complicated. The first step is to take care of those cavities and miss-shaped or missing teeth.  The second step is to straighten the teeth.  This can be done with braces or Invisalign.  Then, if the teeth are a little dingy (read—they look straight, but are still a really nasty yellow), the teeth are bleached to a pleasing shade, and voila’!  A nice white smile.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bleaching can be done in several ways.  One is in-office bleaching.  This has its pros and cons.  The main benefit is that you walk into the office with dingy teeth, and walk out an hour and a half later with a nice white smile.  The downside is that it is more expensive than other methods, and to some people the process is a little uncomfortable.  A plastic curtain (rubber dam) is placed over the teeth to protect the gums, and bleaching material is placed on the teeth for ten to fifteen minutes.  It is rinsed off and applied again.  This process is done until the teeth reach the desired shade.  It used to be that a bright light was used to enhance the process, or so people thought. But the light was shown to be totally unnecessary.  (Some people call the light thing a bit of a scam, but that’s a little strong.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Whitening tray&quot; class=&quot;float-right&quot; src=&quot;/sites/default/files/styles/blog_third_width/public/blog/Bleach%201.jpg?itok=9iNQBgWw&quot; title=&quot;Brighten That Smile with a whitening tray&quot; width=&quot;193&quot; height=&quot;132&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The way we find that combines ease of use, less expense, and great results is to fabricate clear plastic trays and let our patients wear them at home with a little special bleach in them for about a half hour.  This is repeated over a few days until the desired shade is reached.   An added bonus to doing it this way is that the patients keep the trays.   If there is a little relapse, they can put bleach in them, and touch the teeth up.  Inexpensive touch up kits are available for this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another method for bleaching is with whitening strips that can be bought in drug stores.  We find that this does not give the good results that the other methods provide.  They don’t seem to get into all the nooks and crevices of the teeth.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A lot of our patients ask about whitening toothpastes.  These are great aids to keep teeth white after bleaching, but don’t do much to whiten teeth that are dingy looking to begin with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another question we get is about sensitivity. Sometimes after bleaching of any type, a little sensitivity can result.  This is easily corrected with sensitivity tooth paste placed in the bleaching tray fifteen minutes for a day or two.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, take a long look in the mirror and smile at yourself.  If you like what you see, go out and have a great day.  If your smile just doesn’t do much for you, &lt;a href=&quot;http://ingedental.com/contact&quot;&gt;contact us&lt;/a&gt; or give our office a call (610-250-6411), and we’ll have you beaming and smiling at everyone you see.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-field-tags field-type-taxonomy-term-reference field-label-above&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-label&quot;&gt;Tags:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-item even&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/tags/teeth-whitening&quot; typeof=&quot;skos:Concept&quot; property=&quot;rdfs:label skos:prefLabel&quot; datatype=&quot;&quot;&gt;teeth whitening&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
 <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2015 15:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Dr. Inge</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">131 at http://ingedental.com</guid>
 <comments>http://ingedental.com/blog/brighten-smile#comments</comments>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
