<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xml:base="http://ingedental.com"  xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<channel>
 <title>Andrew Inge - welcome</title>
 <link>http://ingedental.com/tags/welcome</link>
 <description></description>
 <language>en</language>
<item>
 <title>A Great Dental Experience, not Just a Dental Appointment.</title>
 <link>http://ingedental.com/blog/great-dental-experience-not-just-dental-appointment</link>
 <description>&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-body field-type-text-with-summary field-label-hidden&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-item even&quot; property=&quot;content:encoded&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;It is a great time for dental patients. Modern dentistry can help so many people in so many ways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I mentioned in our last post, dentistry is not the same as it was just a few years ago. And who benefits the most from this? You do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One constant in life is that the pace of change in almost every sphere is getting faster and faster. This is true in dentistry for sure. Remember how George Washington had to pull every single one of his teeth without any anesthetic? Well, things really didn&#039;t change much for over one hundred years. Sometime I should go over the high points of the history of dentistry, because it is interesting, but for now let&#039;s just say &quot;It ain&#039;t like the old days!&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/sites/default/files/blog/Stacey_0.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Stacey&quot; title=&quot;Stacey&quot; width=&quot;120&quot; height=&quot;160&quot; class=&quot;float-right&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The advances in today&#039;s dentistry are not just about the technology, although the technology is a big part of it. The focus is on the entire dental experience. In the last post I wrote about how even your phone call is handled differently. But that is just the starting point. If you are a new patient, most modern dental offices will let you send in your new patient registration and medical history information beforehand either online or by mail. This saves you a lot of time and hassles on your first visit. When you walk into the office you are welcomed with a warm greeting. The old sliding glass door and &quot;name, please&quot; welcome is a thing of the past.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &quot;waiting room&quot; is not actually a &quot;waiting&quot; room, although the name has kind of stuck. (Most dentists these days make a huge effort to be right on schedule with minimal waiting.) The room, whatever you want to call it, is well lit and patient friendly. You will right away notice the cleanliness and up to date reading materials. There is usually a corner with children&#039;s toys.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The whole atmosphere has the feeling of a warm welcome, not a cold medical facility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The whole focus is on you and making your visit a great experience, not just a dental appointment.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-field-tags field-type-taxonomy-term-reference field-label-above&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-label&quot;&gt;Tags:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-item even&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/tags/welcome&quot; typeof=&quot;skos:Concept&quot; property=&quot;rdfs:label skos:prefLabel&quot; datatype=&quot;&quot;&gt;welcome&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-item odd&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/tags/first-visit&quot; typeof=&quot;skos:Concept&quot; property=&quot;rdfs:label skos:prefLabel&quot; datatype=&quot;&quot;&gt;fIrst visit&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-item even&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/tags/changes-dentistry&quot; typeof=&quot;skos:Concept&quot; property=&quot;rdfs:label skos:prefLabel&quot; datatype=&quot;&quot;&gt;changes in dentistry&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
 <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jan 2013 03:13:51 +0000</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Dr. Inge</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">118 at http://ingedental.com</guid>
 <comments>http://ingedental.com/blog/great-dental-experience-not-just-dental-appointment#comments</comments>
</item>
<item>
 <title>Welcome to My Blog</title>
 <link>http://ingedental.com/blog/welcome-my-blog</link>
 <description>&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-body field-type-text-with-summary field-label-hidden&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-item even&quot; property=&quot;content:encoded&quot;&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;float-left&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/sites/default/files/blog/logo_sm.png&quot; alt=&quot;abstract tooth&quot; title=&quot;Tooth&quot; width=&quot;150&quot; height=&quot;138&quot; class=&quot;float-right&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Welcome to my blog!&lt;/strong&gt; Dentistry is both a science and an art. We have capabilities never dreamed of even 50 years ago. It is a great time to be a dentist. And it is a great time to be a dental patient. Modern dentistry can help so many people in so many ways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&#039;s face it. A visit to the dentist is not on most people&#039;s &quot;top ten things I like to do&quot; list. It seems some kind of fear of going to the dentist is instilled in people at a very young age, like maybe along with wondering about the boogey man under the bed. And do you know what? This fear was fully justified up until the past twenty years or so. Dentistry was something to be afraid of. It hurt! And the sound of the drill, and all the sharp instruments laying around. I could go on, but those of you of the squeamish sort out there might stop reading.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The good news is…times have changed! The change can be seen from the very first phone call. How many of you remember the dental office phone ringing ten times before some answering machine puts you on hold for five minutes. Then the sweet voice on the other end of the line gives an almost comatose version of &quot;Doctor&#039;s office&quot;. It feels like, wow, I&#039;m sorry I interrupted your nap. Ask for an appointment? Sure, there&#039;s an opening about three weeks down the road. Having pain? Well, maybe we can move it up until two weeks, but we&#039;ll be squeezing you in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not anymore. Call a dental office now and the phone will answer in two or three rings with a live person on the end—&quot;Dr. Inge&#039;s office. This is Stacey. How can I help you?&quot; (Actually, most modern dental offices are like that now. I just use our office because I know the names.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So...that&#039;s just the beginning. In future blogs we are going to get into some of the new ideas, techniques, and technology that make going to the dentist a very pleasant experience. We&#039;ll discuss bonding, tooth colored fillings and crowns, root canals, and more. If there are any questions you may have concerning something written here, or actually about anything at all, please feel free to ask.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Dental Tips&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People will come into our office with many types of pain. It&#039;s the dentist&#039;s job to sort things out and determine the cause of the pain in order to help relieve it. I usually ask a series of questions that tell me a lot about what is going on:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Does hot and/or cold create the pain? This is an important thing to know to help locate the pain, but because so many things can cause hot and cold sensitivity more information is needed to determine the exact cause. (Tooth sensitivity can be caused by gum recession, cavities, abscesses, grinding of teeth and other things.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Does it hurt when you eat or bite down? This can be caused by a deep cavity or even food being jammed in between teeth. If biting on a tooth creates sharp, BIG TIME pain, it could mean there is a crack in the tooth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Does the tooth ache or throb spontaneously, like when you are doing nothing but watching TV? Does it wake you up at night? This could be because of the dying nerve of a tooth or an infection. If there is any swelling, it is possible for the pain to lessen, but infections can be bad news, so be sure to call us right away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Does the jaw ache just in front of the ear? This can be related to TMD, or Temporomandibular Joint Disorder, or what some people call TMJ problems. TMD can be caused by a variety of factors that have to be investigated. Impacted third molars can also cause an ache in the jaw. A more worrisome thing about sudden jaw pain is that it can be the sign of an impending heart attack, especially in women, so it is important that it be evaluated immediately.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do your gums bleed when you brush your teeth? This can be the sign of gum disease.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are some of the more important questions we ask when patients come in with pain. Sometimes dentistry is like tough detective work, but it is rewarding for the dentist, and especially the patient, when the cause of pain can be determined, and then relieved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Callie&#039;s Corner&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In our office we have computer monitors in each room. When we are not using them for clinical purposes we have a stream of non-dental photographs taken by our staff members. These are usually pictures of vacations, family events, etc. As it turns out, just about every staff person has a dog. Or two or three dogs. In fact, I myself have a four year old Welsh Corgi named Callie. Every day we are asked some questions about the photos we show (and maybe about our dogs). So, on each blog post I plan on writing a paragraph about some of the non-dental activities going on in our office. We&#039;ll call it Callie&#039;s Corner.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-field-tags field-type-taxonomy-term-reference field-label-above&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-label&quot;&gt;Tags:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-item even&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/tags/welcome&quot; typeof=&quot;skos:Concept&quot; property=&quot;rdfs:label skos:prefLabel&quot; datatype=&quot;&quot;&gt;welcome&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
 <pubDate>Thu, 29 Nov 2012 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Dr. Inge</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">117 at http://ingedental.com</guid>
 <comments>http://ingedental.com/blog/welcome-my-blog#comments</comments>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
