<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xml:base="http://ingedental.com"  xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<channel>
 <title>Andrew Inge - resolutions</title>
 <link>http://ingedental.com/tags/resolutions</link>
 <description></description>
 <language>en</language>
<item>
 <title>New Year&#039;s Resolutions</title>
 <link>http://ingedental.com/blog/new-years-resolutions</link>
 <description>&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-body field-type-text-with-summary field-label-hidden&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-item even&quot; property=&quot;content:encoded&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/sites/default/files/blog/Resolution%20Reminder_1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;New Year&amp;#039;s Resolution Reminders&quot; title=&quot;New Year&amp;#039;s Resolution Reminders&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; height=&quot;135&quot; class=&quot;float-right&quot; /&gt;Well, we are a few weeks into the new year. How is everyone doing with their New Year&#039;s resolutions? Chances are you have already begun to break some of your resolutions. It&#039;s OK, everyone does it. That&#039;s why the gyms are so crowded on January 2 and practically ghost towns on January 31.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are five resolutions that you may have made this year that is said we should absolutely not want to break (no guilt trip intended) Here&#039;s a brief outline:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I will lose weight.&lt;/strong&gt; Easier said than done. That&#039;s why over a third of Americans are clinically obese. Here&#039;s a quick tip. It&#039;s all about the eating and not as much about the exercise. That does not mean we don&#039;t believe in exercise. (You don&#039;t have to be a jock to walk on the tread mill a few minutes every day.) But when it comes down to purely losing weight we need to adjust our eating program. It could just mean putting smaller portions in front of us before we start to eat. And then don&#039;t go back for seconds. It really does work, and is a resolution we don&#039;t want to give up on!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I&#039;m not going to spend more money than I make.&lt;/strong&gt; Don&#039;t break this one. It&#039;s crucial. It comes down to being disciplined, just like resolution #1 above. Discipline over a month becomes a habit, and then it&#039;s pretty much clear sailing. If you can make a point to spend less than you make and really start socking the extra cash away into savings, your life really will be less stressful. And that is a guarantee.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I will put people before material possessions and money.&lt;/strong&gt; Never love anything that can&#039;t love you back.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I will forgive others.&lt;/strong&gt; Not much more we can say here, except for the fact that it has been proven that those of us who forgive are much more at peace than those who do not.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I will make an appointment for a dental checkup and cleaning every six months.&lt;/strong&gt; This habit offers one of the best ROLs there is. (For those who are not into three letter anagrams, that means Return On Investments.) It saves you money. It saves you time. It&#039;s a great benefit to your overall health. It either makes or preserves a terrific smile, affecting your self-confidence and appearance.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;So there you have it. Of course, feel free to add to this list. There are many ways we can be better people. And continue to have a great New Year!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-field-tags field-type-taxonomy-term-reference field-label-above&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-label&quot;&gt;Tags:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-item even&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/tags/new-year&quot; typeof=&quot;skos:Concept&quot; property=&quot;rdfs:label skos:prefLabel&quot; datatype=&quot;&quot;&gt;new year&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-item odd&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/tags/resolutions&quot; typeof=&quot;skos:Concept&quot; property=&quot;rdfs:label skos:prefLabel&quot; datatype=&quot;&quot;&gt;resolutions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
 <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jan 2013 15:25:19 +0000</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Dr. Inge</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">121 at http://ingedental.com</guid>
 <comments>http://ingedental.com/blog/new-years-resolutions#comments</comments>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
